<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-01T21:14:44+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jeroen Rijks</title><subtitle>Jeroen's blog</subtitle><author><name>Jeroen Rijks</name></author><entry><title type="html">How I started my career</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/01/starting-my-career.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I started my career" /><published>2020-03-01T14:52:13+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-01T14:52:13+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/01/starting-my-career</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/01/starting-my-career.html">&lt;p&gt;I started my career as a backend developer for a technical consultancy called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solirius.com&quot;&gt;Solirius Consulting&lt;/a&gt;. After a year of learning on the job, supplemented with dedicated learning in a supportive environment, I built up enough experience with Java, Python, and various DevOps tools, to call myself a competent software engineer. However, the most important things that I learned at Solirius are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/link_to_headphones_on/off&quot;&gt;the importance of good communication skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an understanding of how to work with other people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what I want my career to look like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solirius&quot;&gt;Solirius&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Solirius, I worked on the &lt;a href=&quot;www.moj.com/reform&quot;&gt;digitalisation of the Ministry of Justice&lt;/a&gt;, which was a large-scale project, in which our microservice team provided utility APIs to approximately 10 other microservice teams. A centralised platform engineering team provided a platform for each microservice to deploy onto, and was following the industry-wide trend to host microservices on Kubernetes. Given a lot of freedom to select my own tasks, I chose to set up our Kubernetes manifests, and subsequently learnt my way around Kubernetes, Helm, Azure and Jenkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After learning more about DevOps, I realised that despite spending so much time with Kubernetes, I still didn’t feel like I had any ownership of what I had created. It was this, combined with the desire to become a Kubernetes god, that made me decide to leave Solirius, in pursuit of a career in DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transreport&quot;&gt;Transreport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2019, I joined &lt;a href=&quot;www.transreport.co.uk&quot;&gt;TransReport&lt;/a&gt;, a small startup working on an awesome product, Passenger Assist. Working with some amazing people in our London, Glasgow and Romanian offices, we have created a system that will help rail companies to provide assistance to disabled travellers throughout the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, my responsibility is to make sure that the docker images I’m given run successfully, prioritising reliability, security, and scalability. This blog should end up with a lot of stories I’m going to write more about my DevOps adventure on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeroen Rijks</name></author><summary type="html">I started my career as a backend developer for a technical consultancy called Solirius Consulting. After a year of learning on the job, supplemented with dedicated learning in a supportive environment, I built up enough experience with Java, Python, and various DevOps tools, to call myself a competent software engineer. However, the most important things that I learned at Solirius are: the importance of good communication skills an understanding of how to work with other people what I want my career to look like</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ownership of a product</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/15/jeroen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ownership of a product" /><published>2020-02-15T14:52:13+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-15T14:52:13+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/15/jeroen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/15/jeroen.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.com/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; is a thing I use to run apps on servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;this = example.code
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this is an example of some &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;output&lt;/code&gt; that you could make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;subtitle&quot;&gt;Subtitle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;malala&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeroen Rijks</name></author><summary type="html">Kubernetes is a thing I use to run apps on servers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ownership of a product</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/15/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ownership of a product" /><published>2020-02-15T14:52:13+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-15T14:52:13+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/15/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/15/first-post.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-much-time-should-developers-spend-in-meetings&quot;&gt;How much time should developers spend in meetings?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devs should feel ownership of the product. This is for motivational reasons.
Devs don’t like spending time in meetings - they chose to be devs because they like coding, not talking.
Benefits of ownership&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;example of a code snippet
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Jeroen Rijks</name></author><summary type="html">How much time should developers spend in meetings?</summary></entry></feed>